<release date="2015-09-14" version="0.82" title="Refactoring, Command-line Help, and Minor Bug Fixes">
    <release-core-list>
        <release-bug-list>
            <release-item>
                <p>Fixed an issue where resumed compressed backups were not preserving existing files.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <p>Fixed an issue where resume and incr/diff would not ensure that the prior backup had the same compression and hardlink settings.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <p>Fixed an issue where a cold backup using <setting>{[dash]}-no-start-stop</setting> could be started on a running <postgres/> cluster without <setting>{[dash]}-force</setting> specified.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <p>Fixed an issue where a thread could be started even when none were requested.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <p>Fixed an issue where the <backrest/> version number was not being updated in <file>backup.info</file> and <file>archive.info</file> after an upgrade/downgrade.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <release-item-contributor-list>
                    <release-item-ideator id="stephen.frost"/>
                </release-item-contributor-list>

                <p>Fixed an issue where the <cmd>info</cmd> command was throwing an exception when the repository contained no stanzas.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <release-item-contributor-list>
                    <release-item-ideator id="stephen.frost"/>
                </release-item-contributor-list>

                <p>Fixed an issue where the <postgres/> <code>pg_stop_backup()</code> NOTICEs were being output to <id>stderr</id>.</p>
            </release-item>
        </release-bug-list>

        <release-feature-list>
            <release-item>
                <p>Experimental support for <postgres/> 9.5 alpha2. This may break when the control version or WAL magic changes in future versions but will be updated in each <backrest/> release to keep pace. All regression tests pass except for <setting>{[dash]}-target-resume</setting> tests (this functionality has changed in 9.5) and there is no testing yet for <file>.partial</file> WAL segments.</p>
            </release-item>
        </release-feature-list>

        <release-improvement-list>
            <release-item>
                <p>Renamed <setting>recovery-setting</setting> option and section to <setting>recovery-option</setting> to be more consistent with <backrest/> naming conventions.</p>
            </release-item>

            <release-item>
                <p>Added dynamic module loading to speed up commands, especially asynchronous archiving.</p>
            </release-item>
        </release-improvement-list>

        <release-development-list>
            <release-item>
                <p>Code cleanup and refactoring to standardize on patterns that have evolved over time.</p>
            </release-item>
        </release-development-list>
    </release-core-list>

    <release-doc-list>
        <release-feature-list>
            <release-item>
                <p>Command-line help is now extracted from the same XML source that is used for the other documentation and includes much more detail.</p>
            </release-item>
        </release-feature-list>
    </release-doc-list>

    <release-test-list>
        <release-development-list>
            <release-item>
                <p>Expiration tests are now synthetic rather than based on actual backups. This will allow development of more advanced expiration features.</p>
            </release-item>
        </release-development-list>
    </release-test-list>
</release>
