<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE doc SYSTEM "doc.dtd">
<doc title="{[project]}" subtitle="Coding Standards" toc="y">
    <description>{[project]} Coding Standard.</description>

    <section id="standards">
        <title>Standards</title>

        <section id="indentation">
            <title>Indentation</title>

            <p>Indentation is four spaces -- no tabs.  Only file types that absolutely require tabs (e.g. `Makefile`) may use them.</p>
        </section>

        <section id="line-length">
            <title>Line Length</title>

            <p>With the exception of documentation code, no line of any code or test file shall exceed 132 characters. If a line break is required, then it shall be after the first function parenthesis:</p>

            <code-block>
// CORRECT - location of line break after first function parenthesis if line length is greater than 132
StringList *removeList = infoBackupDataLabelList(
    infoBackup, strNewFmt("^%s.*", strZ(strLstGet(currentBackupList, fullIdx))));

// INCORRECT
StringList *removeList = infoBackupDataLabelList(infoBackup, strNewFmt("^%s.*", strZ(strLstGet(currentBackupList,
    fullIdx))));
            </code-block>

            <p>If a conditional, then after a completed conditional, for example:</p>

            <code-block>
// CORRECT - location of line break after a completed conditional if line length is greater than 132
if (archiveInfoPgHistory.id != backupInfoPgHistory.id ||
    archiveInfoPgHistory.systemId != backupInfoPgHistory.systemId ||
    archiveInfoPgHistory.version != backupInfoPgHistory.version)

// INCORRECT
if (archiveInfoPgHistory.id != backupInfoPgHistory.id || archiveInfoPgHistory.systemId !=
    backupInfoPgHistory.systemId || archiveInfoPgHistory.version != backupInfoPgHistory.version)
            </code-block>
        </section>

        <section id="function-comment">
            <title>Function Comments</title>

            <p>Comments for <code>extern</code> functions should be included in the <file>.h</file> file. Comments for <code>static</code> functions and implementation-specific notes for <code>extern</code> functions (i.e., not of interest to the general user) should be included in the <file>.c</file> file.</p>
        </section>

        <section id="inline-comment">
            <title>Inline Comment</title>

            <p>Inline comments shall start at character 69 and must not exceed the line length of 132. For example:</p>

            <code-block>
typedef struct InlineCommentExample
{
    const String *comment;                                          // Inline comment example
    const String *longComment;                                      // Inline comment example that exceeds 132 characters should
                                                                    // then go to next line but this should be avoided
} InlineCommentExample;
            </code-block>
        </section>

        <section id="naming">
            <title>Naming</title>

            <section id="variables">
                <title>Variables</title>

                <p>Variable names use camel case with the first letter lower-case.</p>

                <list>
                    <list-item><id>stanzaName</id> - the name of the stanza</list-item>
                    <list-item><id>nameIdx</id> - loop variable for iterating through a list of names</list-item>
                </list>

                <p>Variable names should be descriptive.  Avoid <id>i</id>, <id>j</id>, etc.</p>
            </section>

            <section id="types">
                <title>Types</title>

                <p>Type names use camel case with the first letter upper case:

                <code>typedef struct MemContext &lt;...&gt;</code>

                <code>typedef enum {&lt;...&gt;} ErrorState;</code></p>
            </section>

            <section id="constants">
                <title>Constants</title>

                <p><b>#define Constants</b></p>

                <p><code>#define</code> constants should be all caps with <id>_</id> separators.</p>

                <code-block type="c">
#define MY_CONSTANT                                                 "STRING"
                </code-block>

                <p>The value should be aligned at column 69 whenever possible.</p>

                <p>This type of constant should mostly be used for strings.  Use enums whenever possible for integer constants.</p>

                <p><b>String Constants</b></p>

                <p>String constants can be declared using the <code>STRING_STATIC()</code> macro for local strings and <code>STRING_EXTERN()</code> for strings that will be extern'd for use in other modules.</p>

                <p>Extern'd strings should be declared in the header file as:</p>

                <code-block type="c">
#define SAMPLE_VALUE                                                "STRING"
    STRING_DECLARE(SAMPLE_VALUE_STR);
                </code-block>

                <p>And in the C file as:</p>

                <code-block type="c">
STRING_EXTERN(SAMPLE_VALUE_STR,                                     SAMPLE_VALUE);
                </code-block>

                <p>Static strings declared in the C file are not required to have a <code>#define</code> if the <code>#define</code> version is not used.  Extern'd strings must always have the <code>#define</code> in the header file.</p>

                <p><b>Enum Constants</b></p>

                <p>Enum elements follow the same case rules as variables. They are strongly typed so this shouldn't present any confusion.</p>

                <code-block type="c">
typedef enum
{
    cipherModeEncrypt,
    cipherModeDecrypt,
} CipherMode;
                </code-block>

                <p>Note the comma after the last element.  This reduces diff churn when new elements are added.</p>
            </section>

            <section id="macros">
                <title>Macros</title>

                <p>Macro names should be upper-case with underscores between words. Macros (except simple constants) should be avoided whenever possible as they make code less clear and test coverage harder to measure.</p>

                <p>Macros should follow the format:</p>

                <code-block type="c">
#define MACRO(paramName1, paramName2)   \
    &lt;code&gt;
                </code-block>

                <p>If the macro defines a block it should look like:</p>

                <code-block type="c">
#define MACRO_2(paramName1, paramName2) \
{                                       \
    &lt;code&gt;                              \
}
                </code-block>

                <p>Continuation characters should be aligned at column 132 (unlike the examples above that have been shortened for display purposes).</p>

                <p>To avoid conflicts, variables in a macro will be named <id>[macro name]_[var name]</id>, e.g. <id>TEST_RESULT_resultExpected</id>. Variables that need to be accessed in wrapped code should be provided accessor macros.</p>

                <p><link section="/language-elements/variadic-functions">Variadic functions</link> are an exception to the capitalization rule.</p>
            </section>

            <section id="begin-end">
                <title>Begin / End</title>

                <p>Use <id>Begin</id> / <id>End</id> for names rather than <id>Start</id> / <id>Finish</id>, etc.</p>
            </section>

            <section id="new-free">
                <title>New / Free</title>

                <p>Use <id>New</id> / <id>Free</id> for constructors and destructors rather than <id>Create</id> / <id>Destroy</id>, etc.</p>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section id="formatting">
            <title>Formatting</title>

            <section id="braces">
                <title>Braces</title>

                <p>C allows braces to be excluded for a single statement.  However, braces should be used when the control statement (if, while, etc.) spans more than one line or the statement to be executed spans more than one line.</p>

                <p>No braces needed:</p>

                <code-block type="c">
if (condition)
    return value;
                </code-block>

                <p>Braces needed:</p>

                <code-block type="c">
if (conditionThatUsesEntireLine1 &amp;&amp;
    conditionThatUsesEntireLine2)
{
    return value;
}
                </code-block>

                <code-block type="c">
if (condition)
{
    return
        valueThatUsesEntireLine1 &amp;&amp;
        valueThatUsesEntireLine2;
}
                </code-block>

                <p>Braces should be added to <code>switch</code> statement cases that have a significant amount of code. As a general rule of thumb, if the code block in the <code>case</code> is large enough to have blank lines and/or multiple comments then it should be enclosed in braces.</p>

                <code-block type="c">
switch (int)
{
    case 1:
        a = 2;
        break;

    case 2:
    {
        # Comment this more complex code
        a = 1;
        b = 2;

        c = func(a, b);

        break;
    }
}
                </code-block>
            </section>

            <section id="hints-warnings-errors">
                <title>Hints, Warnings, and Errors</title>

                <p>Hints are to be formatted with capitalized <id>HINT:</id> followed by a space and a sentence. The sentence shall only begin with a capital letter if the first word is an acronym (e.g. TLS) or a proper name (e.g. PostgreSQL). The sentence must end with a period, question mark or exclamation point as appropriate.</p>

                <p>Warning and errors shall be lowercase with the exceptions for proper names and acronyms and end without punctuation.</p>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="language-elements">
        <title>Language Elements</title>

        <section id="data-types">
            <title>Data Types</title>

            <p>Don't get exotic - use the simplest type that will work.

            Use <id>int</id> or <id>unsigned int</id> for general cases. <id>int</id> will be at least 32 bits. When not using <id>int</id> use one of the types defined in <file>common/type.h</file>.</p>
        </section>

        <section id="macros">
            <title>Macros</title>

            <p>Don't use a macro when a function could be used instead.  Macros make it hard to measure code coverage.</p>
        </section>

        <section id="objects">
            <title>Objects</title>

            <p>Object-oriented programming is used extensively.  The object pointer is always referred to as <id>this</id>.</p>

            <p>An object can expose internal struct members by defining a public struct that contains the members to be exposed and using inline functions to get/set the members.</p>

            <p>The header file:</p>

            <code-block type="c">
/***********************************************************************************************************************************
Getters/setters
***********************************************************************************************************************************/
typedef struct ListPub
{
    unsigned int listSize;                                          // List size
} ListPub;

// List size
__attribute__((always_inline)) static inline unsigned int
lstSize(const List *const this)
{
    return THIS_PUB(List)->listSize;
}
            </code-block>

 <p><code>THIS_PUB()</code> ensures that <code>this != NULL</code> so there is no need to check that in the calling function.</p>

            <p>And the C file:</p>

            <code-block type="c">
struct List
{
    ListPub pub;                                                    // Publicly accessible variables
    ...
};
            </code-block>

            <p>The public struct must be the first member of the private struct. The naming convention for the public struct is to add <id>Pub</id> to the end of the private struct name.</p>
        </section>

        <section id="variadic-functions">
            <title>Variadic Functions</title>

            <p>Variadic functions can take a variable number of parameters.  While the <code>printf()</code> pattern is variadic, it is not very flexible in terms of optional parameters given in any order.</p>

            <p>This project implements variadic functions using macros (which are exempt from the normal macro rule of being all caps).  A typical variadic function definition:</p>

            <code-block type="c">
typedef struct StoragePathCreateParam
{
    bool errorOnExists;
    bool noParentCreate;
    mode_t mode;
} StoragePathCreateParam;

#define storagePathCreateP(this, pathExp, ...)                              \
    storagePathCreate(this, pathExp, (StoragePathCreateParam){__VA_ARGS__})
#define storagePathCreateP(this, pathExp)                                  \
    storagePathCreate(this, pathExp, (StoragePathCreateParam){0})

void storagePathCreate(const Storage *this, const String *pathExp, StoragePathCreateParam param);
            </code-block>

            <p>Continuation characters should be aligned at column 132 (unlike the example above that has been shortened for display purposes).</p>

            <p>This function can be called without variable parameters:</p>

            <code-block type="c">
storagePathCreateP(storageLocal(), "/tmp/pgbackrest");
            </code-block>

            <p>Or with variable parameters:</p>

            <code-block type="c">
storagePathCreateP(storageLocal(), "/tmp/pgbackrest", .errorOnExists = true, .mode = 0777);
            </code-block>

            <p>If the majority of functions in a module or object are variadic it is best to provide macros for all functions even if they do not have variable parameters.  Do not use the base function when variadic macros exist.</p>
        </section>
<!-- CSHANG MOVE THESE TO CONTRIBUTING -->
        <section id="memory-context">
            <title>Memory Context</title>

            <p>Memory is allocated inside contexts and can be long lasting (for objects) or temporary (for functions). In general, use <code>MEM_CONTEXT_NEW_BEGIN("somename")</code> for objects and <code>MEM_CONTEXT_TEMP_BEGIN()</code> for functions. See <file>src/common/memContext.h</file> for more details and the <link section="/coding-example">Coding Example</link> below.</p>

        </section>

        <section id="message-logging">
            <title>Logging</title>

            <p>Logging is used in debugging with the built-in macros FUNCTION_LOG_* and FUNCTION_TEST_*, which are used to trace parameters passed to/returned from functions. FUNCTION_LOG_* macros are used for production logging whereas FUNCTION_TEST_* macros will be compiled out of production code. For functions where no parameter is valuable for debugging in production, use <code>FUNCTION_TEST_BEGIN()/FUNCTION_TEST_END()</code>, else use <code>FUNCTION_LOG_BEGIN(someLogLevel)/FUNCTION_LOG_END()</code>. See <file>src/common/debug.h</file> for more details and the <link section="/coding-example">Coding Example</link> below.</p>

            <p>Logging is also used for providing information to the user via the LOG_* macros, such as <code>LOG_INFO("some informational message")</code> and <code>LOG_WARN_FMT("no prior backup exists, %s backup has been changed to full", strZ(cfgOptionDisplay(cfgOptType)))</code> and also via THROW_* macros when throwing an error. See <file>src/common/log.h</file> and <file>src/common/error.h</file> for more details and the <link section="/coding-example">Coding Example</link> below.</p>

        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="coding-example">
        <title>Coding Example</title>

            <p>In the hypothetical example below, code comments (double-slash or slash-asterisk) will explain the example. Refer to the previous sections of this document for an introduction to the details provided here.</p>

            <section id="coding-ex1">
                <title>Example: basic object construction</title>
                <code-block type="c">
// Declare the publicly accessible variables in a structure named the object name with Pub appended
typedef struct MyObjPub         // First letter upper case
{
    MemContext *memContext;     // Pointer to memContext in which this object resides
    unsigned int myData;        // Contents of the myData variable
} MyObjPub;

// Declare the object type
struct MyObj
{
    MyObjPub pub;               // Publicly accessible variables must be first and named "pub"
    const String *name;         // Pointer to lightweight string object - see string.h
};

// Declare getters and setters inline for the publicly visible variables. Only setters require "Set" appended to the name.
__attribute__((always_inline)) static inline unsigned int
myObjMyData(const MyObj *const this)
{
    return THIS_PUB(MyObj)->myData;    // Use the built-in THIS_PUB macro
}

// Macros for function logging
#define FUNCTION_LOG_MY_OBJ_TYPE                                            \
    MyObj *
#define FUNCTION_LOG_MY_OBJ_FORMAT(value, buffer, bufferSize)               \
    FUNCTION_LOG_STRING_OBJECT_FORMAT(value, myObjToLog, buffer, bufferSize)

// Logging function
String *
myObjToLog(const MyObj *this)
{
    return strNewFmt(
        "{name: %s, myData: %u}", this->name == NULL ? NULL_Z : strZ(this->name), myObjMyData(this));
}

// Object constructor
MyObj *
myObjNew(unsigned int myData, const String *secretName)
{
    FUNCTION_LOG_BEGIN(logLevelDebug);              // Use FUNCTION_LOG_BEGIN with log level display for production code
        FUNCTION_LOG_PARAM(UINT, myData);           // When log level is debug in production, myData variable will be logged
        FUNCTION_TEST_PARAM(STRING, secretName);    // FUNCTION_TEST_PARAM will not display secretName value in production logging
    FUNCTION_LOG_END();

    ASSERT((secretName != NULL || myData > 0);      // Development-only assertions (will be compiled out of production code)

    MyObj *this = NULL;                 // Declare the object in the parent memory context: it will live only as long as the parent

    MEM_CONTEXT_NEW_BEGIN("MyObj")      // Create a long lasting memory context with the name of the object
    {
        this = memNew(sizeof(MyObj));   // Allocate the memory size

        *this = (MyObj)                 // Initialize the object
        {
            .pub =
            {
                .memContext = memContextCurrent(),      // Set the memory context to the current MyObj memory context
                .myData = myData,                       // Copy the simple data type to the this object's memory context
            },
            .name = strDup(secretName),     // Duplicate the String data type to the this object's memory context
        };
    }
    MEM_CONTEXT_NEW_END();

    FUNCTION_LOG_RETURN(MyObj, this);
}

// Function using temporary memory context
String *
myObjDisplay(unsigned int myData)
{
    FUNCTION_TEST_BEGIN();                      // No parameters passed to this functions will be logged in production
        FUNCTION_TEST_PARAM(UINT, myData);
    FUNCTION_TEST_END();

    String *result = NULL;     // Result is created in the current memory context  (referred to as "prior context" below)
    MEM_CONTEXT_TEMP_BEGIN()   // begins a new temporary context
    {
        String *resultStr = strNew("Hello");    // Allocates a string in the temporary memory context

        if (myData > 1)
            resultStr = strCatZ(" World");      // Appends a value to the string still in the temporary memory context
        else
            LOG_WARN("Am I not your World?");   // Logs a warning to the user

        MEM_CONTEXT_PRIOR_BEGIN()           // Switch to the prior context so the duplication of the string is in that context
        {
            result = strDup(resultStr);     // Create a copy of the string in the prior context where "result" was created
        }
        MEM_CONTEXT_PRIOR_END();            // Switch back to the temporary context
    }
    MEM_CONTEXT_TEMP_END();      // Free everything created inside this temporary memory context - i.e resultStr

    FUNCTION_TEST_RETURN(STRING, result);    // Return result but do not log the value in production
}
            </code-block>

            </section>
    </section>

    <section id="testing">
        <title>Testing</title>

        <section id="uncoverable-uncovered">
            <title>Uncoverable/Uncovered Code</title>

            <section id="uncoverable">
                <title>Uncoverable Code</title>

                <p>The <id>uncoverable</id> keyword marks code that can never be covered.  For instance, a function that never returns because it always throws an error.  Uncoverable code should be rare to non-existent outside the common libraries and test code.</p>

                <code-block type="c">
}   // {uncoverable - function throws error so never returns}
                </code-block>

                <p>Subsequent code that is uncoverable for the same reason is marked with <code>// {+uncoverable}</code>.</p>
            </section>

            <section id="uncovered">
                <title>Uncovered Code</title>

                <p>Marks code that is not tested for one reason or another.  This should be kept to a minimum and an excuse given for each instance.</p>

                <code-block type="c">
exit(EXIT_FAILURE); // {uncovered - test harness does not support non-zero exit}
                </code-block>

                <p>Subsequent code that is uncovered for the same reason is marked with `// {+uncovered}`.</p>
            </section>
        </section>
    </section>
</doc>
